What we want to talk about right now is the importance of our linebackers in the 4-3 set against a passing team.
Now most of the time if you are running a 4-3 defense, you are running against a team that runs about as much as they pass.
So these linebackers have to be very athletic and very versatile to be able to adjust to whatever is going on.
So the first responsibility any time the ball is snapped is, our linebackers have to take a step up, they have to search the gaps, they have to pick up to see whether to run the play or if its going to be a pass play.
And they are going to be reading the quarterback.
If the quarterback plays action fakes, a lot of time the linebackers are going to sucked up another step.
So these guys have to be able to react quick.
If it?s not a fake and the quarterback starts a drop back.
These guys first of all have to know their assignments.
The middle linebacker has to drop back, and he is covering in this middle area.
This guys got a big job, because he's got more receivers to his side.
So he's got to cheat to the strong side of the field where there are the majority of the receivers.
And this guy got to try to pick up to see if they are slipping anybody out of the backfield.
Or if this wide receiver is going to cut off on a short route, then this linebackers going to step up.
So he's got the outside responsibilities, the middle linebacker has got anything back here.
But the main thing is, once they read a pass they got to get in a back peddle, pick up the quarterbacks eyes, and then find somebody to cover.
And that's how you play linebacker dropping back in pass coverage.